hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast we
talk about ways for you to grow in your
life and your business to reach your
goals to make more money in your
business and something I want to just
talk about here today is something that
I I see that comes up a lot when I'm
coaching people when I'm working with
them and it's one of the areas that I
think that we can grow past is if you're
somebody who has experienced where
things come easy to you uh or maybe like
you you get results very quickly in
other areas of life it will convince you
that the struggle that it takes to grow
your coaching or course business means
that either you're doing something wrong
you're following the wrong path or
things aren't working right and I and I
would say I was actually somebody who
dealt with this for the longest time is
that I thought that if things take a
while it it means that I'm doing
something wrong or I'm being taught the
wrong way on how to do it and so the
truth is is that when it comes to a
coaching or course business it's a lot
more like the process of gardening to
where the the results that you get are a
lagging indicator of the work that you
do you don't usually do the work and
then ding
instantaneous
gratification um usually you'll do the
work and you won't see anything for a
little while and that is normal the
problem is is most people don't have the
ability to continue doing the work that
actually produces results because
they're not seeing the instant
gratification happen and and and then
they jump to a new idea or they jump to
a new uh strategy shiny object syndrome
as far as this goes and I think that
this this Behavior this becomes almost
like an addictive behavior where we're
seeking after the instant gratification
rather than realizing that if we
consistently did the thing that maybe
isn't producing result as long as we
have a mentor or a coach or somebody
that's helping us that it will
eventually come together to do this now
I often work with a lot of people um
they're in their 40s 50s or 60s and they
say well Jeremiah you know I've been i'
I've been wanting to be successful for
so long I need this to happen right away
because I don't have time to wait for
things to take the time to come together
and I'm just like that thinking right
there
will by definition
make things take longer for you because
you will constantly still be hopping
from thing to thing to thing and so
realize that if maybe you've been
building your business and you want to
find new people that you can reach
online through Facebook ads through L uh
uh social media campaigns and you want
to attract new business to you that
sometimes the process takes longer than
we expect now of course I have seen
success happen in 30 to 60
days I've also seen it take 6 to 12
months before somebody does the
consistent work and sees things start to
come together because they run into
either roadblock or they've tried things
or they done that and really it's all
about the trial and error and the
testing and doing what we call an alpha
release
approach you and adopt an
experimentation mindset which is a
scientific uh strategy where you're
testing you're seeing how does the
marketplace respond how do things come
back to me what are those results and so
I think one of the biggest things that I
that we need to train ourselves on is to
not jump from idea to idea to idea thing
to thing to thing looking for the
immediate gratification and rather
accept that things taking a while to
come together sometimes
is the fastest way that they're going to
come together for
us and and it also just depends on your
Niche and the market some niches have
different restrictions on them when it
comes to advertising uh it can take
longer to do certain things and learning
to develop the resilience and the
patience and not have the unrealistic
and unreasonable expectation of
instantaneous results is one of the
things that's going to help you uh be
successful it's going to help things
come together for you uh more often now
this is an area where when I work with
people when I coach them often times
they get the most emotionally charged
because things they say it feels like
it's one step forward three steps
backwards and things just are not going
how they want them to and and and
usually the person who gets frustrated
disappointed by this is used to
experiencing things working right away
for them in most other areas of their
life and so they feel like okay well
because that's a success strategy that
they've developed and they've realized
okay when I do the right things things
happen quickly for me that they think
that they're not on the right
path I've been I've been in this this
business of coaching courses training
online
training long enough to
know that I've been in the industry for
21 years if you if you wonder how long
I've been in this
industry is that the people who are most
successful often times
struggled in the beginning to gain the
traction that they're having for me it
took
me uh 18 months of pretty much Break
Even
or you know la like not the results that
I expected I was getting with clients
that I would work with 20 times 30 times
the ad spin we would spend
and so I'm like okay I'm going to launch
these offers and I'm going to get I'm
going to make millions and and and I
barely scratch the surface I talk about
my story on this I barely scratched the
surface of making 5,000 or even 10,000 a
month or even $500 a month
sometimes
because I had this expectation that okay
I know how to do all this stuff but it
wasn't working out for me there's two
things that really
uh changed everything is when I started
promoting offers growing my email list
and getting better at sales and selling
and then simultaneously I also worked on
what was the mental blocks that were
stopping me what were the things that
were that were preventing me from taking
action what were the perceptions that I
had based on my life experience see I
had these 21 years of experience
successfully I guess it wasn't 21 years
at the time but 18 19 years of
experience
and success and it wasn't translating to
my own business and it wasn't happening
as quickly as I had seen like nearly
every campaign I ran for clients that
I'd worked with and companies I'd worked
with worked right away right away right
away and and and even people that I was
running their ads for were working right
away but I couldn't get this working for
my own
business and it and it and it actually
correlated to that I was overthinking I
was way too attached with
perfectionism I was not being
assertive in my communication at all
very passive uh very much concerned
about appearing nice to people being too
nice to people worried that they were
going to not like me if I was direct
about
things and this is often what what had
stopped I was way too concerned with
people's approval was a big part of it
as far as that goes make making people
happy with me and and concerned with
that if I did anything wrong that people
didn't like oh my gosh the everything
this just wasn't going to work out and
that effort to do everything perfect was
preventing me from actually seeing
success okay and so then as I got past
that I still didn't see success right
away and that became
frustrating and I would have one
successful campaign and then things did
didn't work out as well and and and and
so it was like I had to really figure
out what was going on beneath the
surface what was really stopping me from
being able to reach people one of the
number one things was that I was not
being uh direct with people was one of
the big
things um and again this might not be
the case for you you might be a very
direct person but maybe you're
struggling with technology or maybe
you're struggling with um your Landing
page or maybe you're struggling with
running the ads or you're struggling
with getting team members that you're
hiring to do the things that that are
going to help you out or maybe you know
you're you're going through learning but
it's not really you're not understanding
it as quickly as you would like to
understand that we all have our own
limitations and I think that when we can
embrace our
limitations it's actually a huge benefit
to us instead of running away from them
instead of being like oh my gosh this is
not working out well that we Embrace
both our strengths and our limits and we
become very clear and very honest with
them and we actually start to appreciate
them you know I actually appreciate some
of my limitations today and I've
structured my business even if it
disappoints certain people that I have
certain
limitations I've I've come to appreciate
them and it's helped me structure my
time my boundaries and create the kind
of life that I want to live and the
business that I want to have as far as
that goes and so that's that's been very
successful but I've had to also grow in
a number of different areas you know
I've been around the personal
development and personal growth space
for years I got started in that space
and yet I've had to learn that like to
to ever think that we have arrived and
that we know everything that there is to
know based on our experience or our
education or how long we've been doing
something that's a very um there was a
mentor that I had she used to say this
if you if you are ripe you're rotten if
you're green you're growing and it's
actually better to see yourself as green
and growing consistently and I still do
this day I see myself as that now I I've
found the balance of having the
confidence in myself when I speak these
messages CU otherwise if I you know if I
wasn't confident nobody would respect
anything that I had to say and that's
just that's not helping anybody to not
help have confidence in what we talk
about uh but at the same time I'm always
open to okay what are new things that I
can learn I was just listening to two
incredible audio books uh today I mean
they were they were amazing that
unlocked new things uh the disease to
please is an incredible audio book by
Harriet
breaker um love that one and then
another one that I was reading as well
the hard thing about hard things by Ben
Horowitz uh was was an incredible audio
book that's all about the hard stuff of
building a business and and his like how
pretty much he lost everything multiple
multiple
times and yet that was actually what got
him to building a company from 0 to $1.6
billion during the hardest time to build
a tech company between the years 2001 to
2007 when everybody said that it was
virtually the stupidest thing in the
world to build one of those businesses
and so I thought that those those books
were amazing I I'm constantly learning
new things and new strategies I don't
want to go off on a tangent on that I
just wanted to just encourage you that
there's always areas that we can grow in
there's always areas that we can become
better even if we're an expert in a
certain field even if we feel like we
know everything about what it takes to
be successful and that we don't have to
learn
anything taking personal ownership of if
something's not working out in my life
how am I able to take responsibility for
that and it's not that it's your fault
right it's not that it's your fault but
for instance if you hire people that
they don't respond to you or they don't
work well with you uh take
responsibility for the fact that you
hired those people and you can always
hire other people and and and and
instead of complaining and wishing that
people were
different except how they are you listen
you're not going to really like change
people by complaining by whining by
saying oh they should be different they
should be doing this differently they
should be offering this or they should
be doing this and this isn't right and I
don't feel served in this way and things
like that instead of focusing in on what
you're not getting from
people
realize that one of the number one ways
that you can grow is to learn how to
take personal
responsibility for what you can control
and listen we can't control other people
no matter how well we are at
manipulating them or talking or
persuading them that that there that
there comes a time where especially if
you're working with good people that are
actually high quality people that
they're that they're not going to be
able to be pushed
around by you saying certain things that
you're used to using to get people to do
the things that you're used to doing and
here's one of the biggest things that
I'm just going to say is that most of
the time a lot of the coaches trainers
and mentors that I meet they're very
good at manipulating other people in
some parts of their life they're very
good at getting their way managing
maintaining controlling the feelings and
emotions of others and it's one of those
areas that you got to learn to let go of
that that for us to get the kind of
sales that we want we actually have to
let go of trying to make the result
happen we control what we can do the
marketing attracting the right client
doing the most
confident sales pit sales message which
by the way is a form of serving people
it's not sleazy it's not slimy it's not
a bad thing at
all to be able to learn how to get
people to buy your coaching and buy your
courses in a
way that gets them to make a decision
and get off the fence to do something
with
you but the truth is we can't control
other people and we got to accept that
fact here's what I found is in my own
business sometimes it takes people two
three four months of interacting with me
listening to my podcasts things like
that before they come around and they
become a client now I have people who
sign up right
away but there's a nurture process as
well and the more consistent we are and
this is the final piece of advice that
I'm going to share
consistency continuing to show up to do
the actions even if you don't see the
result if you consistently do show up
it's a
snowball that actually builds upon
itself and the results start to come in
sometimes a few months down the road and
then because the Snowball Effect is
going and you've stayed consistent that
compounds and grows and you start to see
these crazy results where it's like wow
I'm getting like 30 times return on this
because the Snowball Effect start to
happen I noticed that in my own business
that if I take a month or two off of
marketing
the numbers drop and it's like not that
that
I took the months off of marketing that
necessarily caused that but it's that
I'm not been consistent at showing up
with the people and now I have to start
from Square One often times and so I
actually found for me to work less cuz
that's what I was doing I was taking
breaks pulling back to work
less and and not showing up as
consistently and I found I was having to
work 10 times harder because of that
that actually me staying consistent and
Shoring up and simplifying what I'm
doing but being more consistent at it
actually compounded far more in the long
run and it was and it was a powerful
thing that me taking this big old
elaborate strategy and instead of doing
it every quarter simplifying it down to
one tenth of the effort that I was doing
but doing it every month actually
compounded and produced the kind of
results that we're getting and that's
what we that's if I look back at every
single coaching and course business that
we've built that's been successful it
had an element of that where things
really started to grow is consistently
showing up attracting new people while
serving and simultaneously nurturing the
the the existing ones and putting them
all into this bucket where we're serving
the new people and the existing ones and
we're removing the ones that are not a
good fit for what we're doing and that
compounded over time and compounds and
becomes a successful online course or
coaching
business okay so realize the results
don't always
come in one single sitting but the more
consistent you are the better they are
to compound over time because you end up
building trust with people that they may
not not have signed up with you right
away but they might next month or the
month later or the month after that and
when you can learn to connect with new
people and you make a deep connection
with them that it's not about just
giving them information regurgitating
information but you're actually making a
deep connection with the
people that that's what builds the trust
and trust is what turns into sales in
your
business
okay so hopefully listen I get it this
message is not sexy
I doubt very many people listened all
the way to the end of this podcast
episode because it probably triggered a
lot of different areas in people that
they are dealing with that they are
avoiding they don't want to
hear but it's it's it's so important
that you grasp this that you
understand
that the results you're actually seeking
come from consistent patience and
consistently showing up and not being
sporadic or not jumping from idea to
idea to new idea to new strategy to new
platform to new way of doing things but
it's that it's rather sticking with one
thing that's proven and even if it's not
producing the results right away that
actually the art of sticking with that
thing and what we usually do is we
adjust slightly the ad copy the words
that are in the ads the words that we're
saying in the ad and the words that are
on the landing page we adjust that based
on the feedback that we get from people
so we're we're we're adjusting that that
that becomes fuel that goes on our fire
and then we're able to train the ad
algorithm to attract the right people
that will end up ultimately becoming our
clients and when you put all these
pieces together they create an
incredible coaching or course business
for you and so listen I I want to see
you succeed and the reason why I'm
sharing this is because I believe that
if you start to apply this maybe you've
been struggling to see the results for a
while that if you start to apply what
I've just shared in this episode first
and foremost taking personal
responsibility of what can I do to
improve things instead of becoming
disappointed by having unreasonable or
unrealistic expectations of other people
what you think they should do look at
what can I
do what can I adjust what can I tweak
what can I take charge
of how can I ask better questions how
can I uh be a little bit more resilient
when things don't work out as well how
can I learn
to realize
that success isn't an overnight thing
and that it does take time those are
things that are actually going to
compound and produce great results for
you so I'm excited to see what happens
from those of y'all that are listening
to this
episode and I cannot wait to see
you be successful grow your life
everybody and we'll talk soon have a
good
[Music]
[Applause]
one